M. TAHA METİN



PROFILE

Hi, I'm Muhammed Taha Metin, a dedicated Game Developer. I've contributed to the development of more than 13 games. I've also published a game on Playstore. I've gained experience in OOP with SOLID principles, addressables, scriptable objects, DOTween, trello, photon bolt, design patterns and github.

LANGUAGES

Turkish English Native Fluent

SKILLS

- ✓ Unity Engine
- √ C#
- ✓ Git/ Github
- ✓ Unreal Engine
- ✓ Java
- ✓ Python
- ✓ C
- ✓ Photoshop
- ✓ Fast Writing 70+ wpm

PROJECTS

#FIT IT

Unity, C#. Mobile casual game. The objective of the game is to fit a cubic shape by pushing and rolling it to overcome obstacles. It is currently available on Google Play.

#BULLET RUSH PROTOTYPE

Unity, C#. I have prepared a clone of the Bullet Rush game for a technical interview. Used features; pool system, scriptable objects, singleton, OOP with SOLID.

#MYO ARMBAND DRONE GAME

Unity, C#. As my university graduation project, I developed a drone game that can be played using a Myo armband in the Natural Human-Computer Interaction Laboratory.

#SAMURAİ SUDOKU SOLVER

Unity, C#. I created an application that solves Samurai Sudoku puzzles using threads.

You can find the rest of the projects on tahametin.com

EXPERIENCE

GAME DEVELOPER INTERN - (JUN 2022 - AUG 2022) **NOSURRENDER** – İstanbul, Türkiye

During my internship at NoSurrender company, I contributed to the development of a **real-time mobile strategy** game using **Unity C#**. I had the opportunity to gain experience in various areas including **SOLID principles**, **addressables**, **scriptable objects**, **localization**, Trello, **DOTween**, **Photon Bolt**, **design patterns**, and **GitHub**.

GAME DEVELOPER - (AUG 2020 - FEB 2022)
IEEE CS GAME DEV TEAM - Kocaeli, Türkiye

During my **2 year** participation in the KOU IEEE Computer Science **Game**Development Team, we developed a **top-down shooter** game and an **idle mobile**game with a team of 6 people. I contributed to the coding of the games using

Unity C#. Specifically, I coded parts such as **enemy artificial intelligence**,

pathfinding, and basic mechanics.

EDUCATION

COMPUTER ENGINEERING - (2019-2023) **KOCAELI UNIVERSITY** - Kocaeli, Türkiye

During my studies in computer engineering at Kocaeli University, I learned the fundamental sciences and principles of computer engineering. I worked on projects related to thread management, artificial intelligence, algorithm creation, solving algorithmic problems, as well as basic algorithms and data structures, both individually and in groups.

I participated in student clubs and activities in my field. I attended various bootcamps and technical tours, and I was also part of a game development team.